Guide to the Kore Press Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Kore Press Archive
1994-2006
YCAL MSS 854
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
6.58
(7 boxes)
Production and organizational files, including correspondence, writings, minutes of board meetings, grant proposals, material concerning fundraising and other related papers.
Kore Press
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Kore Press on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 7 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Kore Press
Lisa Bowden and Karen Falkenstrom founded Kore Press in 1993. The press publishes literary (poetry, personal essays, prose and manifestos) works by women writers, with authors including Jennifer Barber, Lucinda Bliss, and Ofelia Zepeda. Kore Press is based in Tucson, Arizona.
Scope and Contents
The Kore Press Archive contains production and organizational files, correspondence, writings, board meeting minutes, grant proposals, material concerning fundraising, and other related papers, dating from 1993 to 2006. The archive documents the work of founders, Lisa Bowden and Karen Falkenstrom, to establish Kore Press, and more broadly, provides insight into an independent press focusing on women's literature at the end of the twentieth and beginning of the twenty-first centuries.
Arrangement
Organized into one grouping: March 2006 Acquisition.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Authors and publishers; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Publishers and publishing; Small presses; Women authors; Born digital; Electronic documents; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Barber, Jennifer; Bliss, Lucinda; Bowden, Lisa; Falkenstrom, Karen; Zepeda, Ofelia; Kore Press
- March 2006 Acquisition, 1; 6.58; (7 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Electronic files removed and logged.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 7 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Production and organizational files, including correspondence, writings, minutes of board meetings, grant proposals, material concerning fundraising and other related papers.
  - Grants
    - Arizona Humanities Council, 2004-2006 (Box 1)
    - Astraea Foundation (Box 1)
    - Community Foundation for Southern Arizona, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Desert Diamond Casino (Box 1)
    - Max and Victoria Dreyfus Foundation (Box 1)
    - Furthermore (Box 1)
    - Gannett Foundation (Box 1)
    - LGBT & S Alliance Foundation (Box 1)
    - Armstrong McDonald Foundation (Box 1)
    - Arizona Commission on the Arts, 2004-2006 (Box 1)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 2006 (Box 1)
    - Open Meadows Foundation (Box 1)
    - Puffin Foundation (Box 1)
    - Soroptimist (Box 1)
    - Southern Foundation, 1999-2005 (Box 1)
    - Stocker Foundation (Box 1)
    - Tuscan Prime Arts Council, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Tuscan Prime Arts Council, 1999-2003 (Box 1)
    - Wallace Foundation of Arizona (Box 1)
    - Witter Bynner Foundation for Poetry (Box 1)
    - Women's Foundation of Southern Arizona, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Amazona Foundation (Box 1)
    - Arizona Bank (Box 1)
    - Arizona Commission on the Arts, 1997-2003 (Box 1)
    - Arizona Commission on the Arts, 1994-1997 (Box 1)
    - Arizon Humanities Council, 1996-2000 (Box 1)
    - The Brico Fund (Box 1)
    - Endowment for the Arts Tuscon, 1999-2002 (Box 1)
    - Barbara Doming / Money for Women Fund (Box 1)
    - CLMP Kolovakas Fund (Box 1)
    - De Grazia Foundation (Box 1)
    - Eric Mathieu Kink Fund (Box 1)
    - McGraw-Hill (Box 1)
    - NFRIG (Box 1)
    - Nina Mason Pullian Charitable Trust (Box 1)
    - Robidoux Foundation (Box 1)
    - The Sister Fund (Box 1)
    - Tucson Arts District Partnership, undated (Box 1)
    - Tuscon Pima Arts Council, 1994-1998 (Box 1)
    - An Uncommon Legacy Foundation (Box 1)
    - Endowment for the Arts of Tuscon, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Incoming Invoices
    - 2001 (Box 1)
    - 2002 (Box 1)
    - 2003 (Box 1)
  - Loose Folders and Unlabelled Material
    - Short-range planning notes (board retreat with Liz Burden), 1997 April (Box 2)
    - Letters of support (Box 2)
    - Fundraising workshop (Box 2)
    - [Unsorted papers] (Box 2)
    - The Sport (Box 2)
    - Permissions contracts, first book, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Permissions (Box 2)
    - [Printing jobs] (Box 2)
    - [Office-related material], 5 (Box 2)
    - Corporate documents, original (Box 2)
    - [Unsorted papers] (Box 2)
    - Redshift Reading press release, emails, etc. (Box 2)
    - Copies of articles (Box 2)
    - Events/publicity logs (Box 2)
    - Poets House (Box 2)
    - Kore Press Press, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Print Publicity, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Print Publicity, 1997-1999 (Box 2)
    - Old Prime Pieces (Box 2)
    - Zepeda, Earth Movements, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Atwood Project (Box 2)
    - Zimmerman Biography (Box 2)
    - Atwood/Zimmerman, 1997 (Box 2)
    - First book entry forms, 2003 (Box 2)
    - [unidentified] (Box 2)
    - Kore Major Donor (Box 2)
    - Goddamn Broken Fundraising (Box 2)
    - Stategic Plan (Box 2)
    - Support Material (letters) and others (Box 2)
    - Lease agreement (13th st.) (Box 2)
    - AZ Corporation Commission (Box 2)
    - Income logs (Box 2)
    - Archive History Items (Box 2)
    - Ling Department Letters/Zepeda PR (Box 2)
    - Ads and invitations (Box 2)
    - Publicity Ops, Lopez-Mills, "While Light Is Built" (Box 2)
    - [Unlabeled] (Box 2)
    - Rooted Heart Review (Box 2)
    - Fundraising Reference Material (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and production, Wilding, A. Rich Piercy, 2004-2005 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 3)
    - Building/Press layout (Box 3)
    - Letters, publicity (Box 3)
    - The Sport (Box 3)
    - Allison Denning biography (Box 3)
    - Kore working files - collecting with Kore (Box 3)
    - Kore working files - booksellers (Box 3)
    - Tender Buttons, 2 (Box 3)
    - Those That Walk the Earth (Box 3)
    - Ueland Fall, 1998 (Box 3)
    - Redshift, Jani Wallace (Box 3)
    - Zelada and Mirocha S., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Permissions
    - Permissions (Box 3)
    - The Monarchs (Box 3)
    - Cartographies (Box 3)
    - Anger (Box 3)
    - Anatomy (Box 3)
    - Earth Movements (Box 3)
    - Goddamn Broken (Box 3)
    - In or Out (Box 3)
    - Ofelia/Mirocha (Box 3)
    - Rooted Heart (Box 3)
    - Shoreline Series (Box 3)
    - Tell Me More (Box 3)
    - Tender Buttons (Box 3)
    - Uses of the Erotic (Box 3)
    - Sarah Zimmerman, 2002 December 10 (Box 3)
    - Jenny Barber (Box 3)
    - Broumas and Begley (Box 3)
    - Lucinda Bliss (Box 3)
    - Becky Byrkit, bio (Box 3)
    - Becky Byrkit, Voice and Range (Box 3)
    - Norma Cole (Box 3)
    - Cully, 3 (Box 3)
    - Deming (Box 3)
    - [unlabelled] (Box 3)
    - Mary Gordon biography (Box 3)
    - Anger Text (Gordon), Jealousy and the Things You Are Not (Box 3)
    - Gregerman, bio (Box 3)
    - Jane Hirschfield (Box 3)
  - Biographies
    - Linda Hogan (Box 3)
    - Kizer (Box 3)
    - Audre Lorde (Box 3)
    - Mendaza (Box 3)
    - Cynthia Miller (Box 3)
    - Paul Mirocha (Box 3)
    - Muluanty (Box 3)
    - Ostheimer (Box 3)
    - Adrienne Rich (Box 3)
    - Silano (Box 3)
    - Stein/Galloway/Halper (Box 3)
    - Tell Me More, Brenda Ueland (Box 3)
    - Jami Wallace (Box 3)
    - Faith Wilding (Box 3)
    - Sylvia Um, 1998 April (Box 4)
    - [Unlabelled] (Box 4)
    - Sheila Murphy (Box 4)
    - Kate Gray (Box 4)
    - Barbara Seyda (Box 4)
    - Wittig (Box 4)
    - Braille (Box 4)
  - Other papers
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Mentoring Spring, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Archive (miscellaneous), 1993-1995 (Box 4)
    - USA's Gripe advice resources (Box 4)
    - Submissions/letters (Box 4)
    - Promotional ideas (Box 4)
    - Grants/production notes (Box 4)
    - Meeting notes, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Board meeting notes, 2004 November 9 (Box 4)
    - Board meeting, 1995-1999 (Box 4)
  - Marketing
    - Inventory notes (Box 4)
    - Distribution and consignment agreements (Box 4)
    - Artist list, book information for old computer (Box 4)
    - Books in print (Box 4)
    - Now (Box 4)
    - Poetry contest: ideas/details (Box 4)
    - Possible distribution, etc. venues (Box 4)
  - Prospective artists
    - Tedi Lopez Mills (Box 4)
    - Jen Bervin (Box 4)
    - Jorie Graham, 1999 February (Box 4)
    - Deb Gregerman (Box 4)
    - Demetria Martinez (Box 4)
    - K. Scriber (photography) (Box 4)
    - Rios resume (Box 4)
    - Joni Wallace (Box 4)
    - Visual artists (Box 4)
    - Witlig (Box 4)
    - Works rejected (Box 4)
    - S. Zimmerman, 1995-1997 (Box 4)
    - Monarchs CD research (Box 4)
    - Monarche butterfly tour (Box 4)
    - Monarche information (Box 4)
    - Uses of the erotic - Lorde (Box 4)
    - Women's Voices Against War, 2003 March (Box 4)
    - Anatomy of Desire (Box 4)
    - [Office-related material] (Box 4)
  - Completed Projects
    - Cleaning Woman (Box 4)
    - Anatomy of Desire (Box 4)
    - Mary Gordon, 1998 Fall (Box 4)
    - Helen Grooves (Box 4)
  - Other Papers
    - Ani concert information (Box 4)
    - [unsorted material including calendar pages] (Box 4)
    - Jane Hirshfield/re-print the weighing, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Ani DiFranco (Box 4)
    - The Monarchs, Otis and McIntosh (Box 4)
  - Interships and other programs
    - Julie Chen, 2003 Spring (Box 4)
    - Interns/volunteers, 2002-2003 (Box 4)
    - Intern information forms (Box 4)
    - Intern program (Box 4)
    - Intern applications, 2000 Fall (Box 4)
    - Interns (evaluations/writing), 1998-1999 (Box 4)
    - Interns (evaluations/writing), 1995-1997 (Box 4)
    - Mentoring, 1998-1999 (Box 4)
    - Volunteers (Box 4)
    - Volunteer information forms (Box 4)
    - Volunteer program (Box 4)
  - Other Papers
    - Catalog development (Box 4)
    - "Goddamn Broken," Atwood (Box 4)
    - Richter (Box 4)
    - Active projects: The Sport, T. Begley (Box 4)
    - Active projects: "Goddamn Broken" (Box 4)
    - Mailing lists (Box 5)
    - Publicity, 1999-2002 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Publicity, 1994-1996 (Box 5)
    - Design, original invitation, 2001 (Box 5)
    - 1993-1996 (Box 5)
    - Press publicity (Box 5)
    - Wire-O, Colts Armory (Box 5)
    - Tracking down rights (Box 5)
    - Order forms (Box 5)
    - Copyright laws (Box 5)
    - Business card artboards (Box 5)
    - Ofelia Zapeda, Earth Movements (Box 5)
    - Ofelia Zepeda (Box 5)
    - "The Sport," poems by T. Begley, 2 (Box 5)
    - "A Path for Rain," Jennifer Barber (Box 5)
    - "Rigging the Wind," Jennifer Barber, 4 (Box 5)
    - Publicity (Box 5)
    - Ofelia's release, 1997 (Box 5)
    - "Rare Printed Mater" (Box 5)
  - Oversize
    - Broadsides, 2 (Box 6)
  - Computer and audiovisual media
    - Computer media
      Restricted fragile material. Refrence copies may be may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - APathforRainupdate.doc, 2006-ycal-0320-a-0001; 1 (Box 7)
        Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - APathforRainfinal.doc, 2006-ycal-0320-a-0002; 1 (Box 7)
      - TREE PAINTING FILES, 2006-ycal-0320-a-0003; 1 (Box 7)
      - Tender Buttons, 2006-ycal-0320-a-0004; 1 (Box 7)
      - NANCY SOLOMON REDSCOV.QXD PC, 2006-ycal-0320-a-0005; 1 (Box 7)
      - NANCY SOLOMON fonts text REDSHIFT, 2006-ycal-0320-a-0006; 1 (Box 7)
      - [no label information], 2006-ycal-0320-a-0007; 1 (Box 7)
      - STRYTLLR.MS 2/1/96, 2006-ycal-0320-a-0008; 1 (Box 7)
      - Dirt. Poems (WP 5.1) Dirt2.Poems, 2006-ycal-0320-a-0009; 1 (Box 7)
      - [no label information], 2006-ycal-0320-a-0010; 1 (Box 7)
      - the sport. + begley, 2006-ycal-0320-a-0011; 1 (Box 7)
      - KORE PRESS 882-7542 HELEN GROVES OLGA BROUMAS T BEGLEY 2-2000 - THE SPORT USES OF THE EROTIC 1993, 2006-ycal-0320-a-0012; 1 (Box 7)
    - Audiovisual media (Box 7)
      Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.